# Ahsan Hussain

Mobile:+44 7423 094757

Email: ranaahsan2007@gmail.com Skype: ranaahsan2007 Room#6 Second floor 9 Pemberton Drive Bradford

BD7 1RA

#### PERSONAL SUMMARY

Computer Science Graduate with over 8 Years of experience in performing mission critical projects. Has the ability to build strong relationships with all stakeholders and to turn proposals into reality. Especially successful in IT roles that demand rigor, a high level of drive, dedication and a focus on delivering business outcomes through the use of latest technologies. Currently studying MSc Data Science with Big Data degree at University of Bradford. Seeking for part time opportunity to enhance my skills.

## Education

Year of Completion	Qualification	Institution
Sep 2019- 2020	MSc Big Data Science	University of Bradford, UK
April, 2017	Mast of Information & Communication Technology	University of Management and Technology Lahore Pakistan
2007-2009	Bachelors of Commerce	Punjab University Lahore Pakistan

#### Skills

- **Analytical Skills** Effectively contributing to company decision-making and highlighting market and industry trends; recommending the best possible solutions for the company stance.
- Presentation Skills Delivering presentations with best of my knowledge and experience to the senior management and across the departments in front of large audiences.
- Problem-Solving Skills Diagnose the key issues and identifying appropriate solutions; resolving
  matters permanently in the given timeframe with proactive approach.
- Teamwork Working independently on different projects and being a team player.
- **Time Management Skills** Prioritizing tasks to run the system smoothly and completing the tasks within deadlines.

## Experience

## Assistant Manager - MIS - Adamjee Insurance Company Limited

(www.adamjeeinsurance.com) March 2014 - Nov 2018

Responsible for project management of multiple projects that includes project initiation, proposals, project delivery, business liaison, stakeholder management, post implementation review and project close out / handover.

- Skilled in Project Management with project planning, execution, monitoring and resource balancing skills with ability to support multiple simultaneous projects.
- Strong analytical and project management skills, including a thorough understanding of how to interpret stake holders business needs and translate them into application and operational requirements.
- Ability to critically evaluate information gathered from multiple sources, reconcile conflicts, decompose high-level information into details, abstract up from low-level information to a general understanding, and distinguish user requests from the underlying true needs.
- Organizing and conducting software business application(s) training for business users.
- Managing technical support on software business application(s).

## Network Engineer – Al Razi Health Care (Project of Abu Dhabi Group)

Jan 2013 - Jan 2014

The main function of Al Razi Health Care is to operate as Hospital and Medical Lab services provider.

• Worked with Al Razi Health Care as Network Support engineer to look after IT support related issues and maintain SLAs with all stake holders.

# IT Service Desk Supervisor – Pepsi Co International Pakistan

April 2007 – Dec 2012

- To manage all the IT related operations which include purchasing of IT related equipment, managing networks, Active Directory, Desktop support, End user issues and all the IT Related documentation.
- Executing Daily backups of Active Directory and Oracle database.
- Configuration and troubleshooting of all network related issues.
- Remote administration of all the 5 locations of PEPSICO Pakistan.
- Dealing with vendors for SLAs of IT equipment.
- Troubleshooting of LAN Network

## **Projects**

- Worked on Takaful Health application deployment as active member for Adamjee Takaful Window Operation.
- UAE health insurance solution system implementation for Adamjee Insurance UAE branch.
- Mobile App Development for insured members with vendor coordinating all phases.
- Successfully deployed Project of core application HIS well-known application for Health Insurance Management in Pakistan.
- Web Portal for Clients to view and track claims status and claim details online.
- Worked as Project lead at University Degree Project (Project Title: MPLS Deployment-Core Networking)
- BI tool Integrations for Management reporting (IBM Cognos)
- MVL (Microsoft Volume Licensing)
- Factory surveillance system installation. 80 rotatable and still cameras

## **Certifications & Training**

- ITIL Foundation Certified in IT Service Management. License #3438360
- Management Development Program (MDP) 3 days course.
- CCNP routing and switching training from Corvit systems.
- Completed CCNA training Dec.2008 from Corvit Systems
- Completed MCSE training from Corvit Systems in Sept'2007
- Hands on experience on HP Open View Service Desk tool which is used for logging of incidents and IT assets tracking.
- Highly experience in dealing with MS Operating systems

## **Interests**

Enjoy listening music and play cricket Keeping up-to-date with current affairs.

### Referees

Names and addresses of two referees are available upon request.